Guide to the Robert J. Hare Powel Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert J. Hare Powel papers
1869-1959
YCAL MSS 494
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.92
(5 boxes)
The papers contain writings and other materials documenting the early career of playwright Robert J. Hare Powel. Writings include scenarios, outlines, and drafts for scripts of stage plays, most of which appear to date from the late-1920s to mid-1930s. Other materials include correspondence, photographs, and a scrapbook documenting Powel's work and theater generally. Correspondence consists of letters to Powel and comments regarding productions of his plays. Photographs consist of stage shots of Yale productions and cartes de visite of actors. The scrapbook contains clippings, printed ephemera, such as theater programs, and photographs.
Powel, Robert Hare (Robert Johnston Hare), 1895-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. H. C. Howells (formerly Powel), 1978.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Robert J. Hare Powel
Robert J. Hare Powel, graduate of the Yale School of Drama (1930) and playwright.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains writings and other material documenting the early career of playwright Robert J. Hare Powel. Writings include scenarios, outlines, and drafts for scripts of stage plays, most of which appear to date from the late-1920s to mid-1930s. Other materials include correspondence, photographs, and a scrapbook documenting Powel's work and theater generally. Correspondence consists of letters to Powel and comments regarding productions of his plays. Photographs consist of stage shots of Yale productions and cartes de visite of actors. The scrapbook contains clippings, printed ephemera, such as theater programs, and photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Writings, 1928-1957. II. Other Material, 1869-1959.
American literature -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Theater -- Production and direction -- United States; Photographic prints; Dramatists; Powel, Robert Hare (Robert Johnston Hare), 1895-; Yale School of Drama
- Writings, 1928-1957; Series I; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Writings contains scenarios, outlines, and drafts, many corrected, for scripts of stage plays, most of which appear to date from the late-1920s to mid-1930s.
  - "Adieu," script, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes illustration
  - "Ain't We Got Fun?" script, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Beware of the Bull," script, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
  - "Brief Candle," script, 1933-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
  - "By Request," script, undated (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
  - "Cross of Ages: An Outline for a Motion Picture", [circa 1934] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Evensong," scripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
  - "Improper Guardianship: A Play in Two Acts," scripts, [1929?]-1935 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Masked," script, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Night's Lodging: A Play in One Act," script, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Paroled," scenario and script, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Prancing Nigger," script, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Taps: A Play in Seven Scenes," scenario and scripts, 1928, undated (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
  - "A Ten-Second Man: A One Act Play," script, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "The Tragedy of the Misfit," script, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "The Unknown Soldier: An Episode in Two Scenes," scripts and other material, 1928-1930, undated (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
    Includes clippings
  - "We Shall Not Sleep," scripts and other material, 1928, undated (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
- Other Material, 1869-1959; Series II; 0.67; (2 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by material type.
  Series II. Other Material contains correspondence, photographs, and a scrapbook documenting Powel's work and theater generally. Correspondence consists of letters to Powel and comments regarding productions of his plays. Photographs consist of stage shots of Yale productions and cartes de visites of actors. The scrapbook contains clippings, printed ephemera, such as theater programs, and photographs.
  - Correspondence, [circa 1927-1959] (Box 4, Folder 34-36)
  - Photographs, 1869-1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 37-40)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1941, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)